Eric O'Callaghan

Linux Engineer

Philadelphia, PA eric@ericoc.com (757) 742-3742

BACKGROUND

I am seeking a technical role, within Philadelphia, that allows me to continuously learn while also making use of my five years of Linux operations experience. I feel that I am excellent at troubleshooting, debugging, and working through production issues making me an ideal systems administrator. I truly love working on the command-line. I prefer a casual, fun, and positive company culture.

EXPERIENCE

Comcast Corporation Linux Engineer

Philadelphia, PA

April 2016 - November 2017

- Performed configuration management by writing Ansible roles and playbooks that I ran on nearly 1,000 CentOS servers which hosted one of the top five largest Splunk installations in the world
- Modified sysctl network and disk I/O settings to utilize servers more efficiently
- Set up a Zabbix cluster which monitored over 800 physical Hewlett-Packard (HP) hosts and was used to automatically detect hard disk drive failures before they caused any service interruption
- Created a variety of complex Apache configurations to fit within internal network security guidelines, including implementation of client-certificate authentication as well as reverse proxies
- Regularly tested TCP/IP connectivity between different VLANs, networks, and data centers
 throughout the country which required opening JIRA tickets to request firewall changes that I
 would then validate were completed successfully
- Ensured consistency of firewall rules as well as server and network settings across hosts in thirty different data centers

Sidecar Interactive

Philadelphia, PA

Linux Systems Administrator

November 2013 - April 2016

- Being the sole systems administrator for the company, my primary duties included response to any infrastructure issues as well as responsibility for all server modifications and yum/apt updates
- Maintained multiple database environments that included MySQL replication between co-located Dell and HP hardware, running Ubuntu, and Amazon Web Services (AWS)
- Wrote and tested documentation on the processes necessary to restore internal Percona XtraDB database backups
- Created and open-sourced a Bash shell script that instantly forwards Zabbix alerts to Slack, which I am proud to say is now used by many members of the Zabbix and Slack online communities
- Automated deployment of in-house PHP application via "chatops". In efforts with a co-worker, we set up RunDeck to trigger requests to the Ansible Tower API allowing quick and easy deployment at any time from our teams shared Slack chat

URBN, Inc

Philadelphia, PA

Linux Systems Administrator

September 2012 - November 2013

- Worked with a team to migrate UrbanOutfitters.com and Anthropologie.com from third-party managed services to in-house physical Solaris and RedHat servers
- Performed racking, cabling, and physical installation of HP servers within the on-site datacenter
- Maintained Apache configurations which proxied web requests to clustered JBoss instances
- Deployed internal DNS resolvers within the e-commerce network to improve response times for all website visitors and transactions while also enhancing network security
- Used Zabbix JMX monitoring to graph HTTP request and response times

Linode, LLC Linux Technical Support

Galloway, NJ July 2010 - August 2012

• Provided quick and helpful technical support to a significant number of customers via telephone, e-mail, and support tickets which involved troubleshooting a wide variety of issues including routing inconsistencies between multiple international data centers

CERTIFICATIONS

- CompTIA Security+, Network+, and Linux+
- Hurricane Electric IPv6 Sage

 Cisco Certified Entry Networking Technician (CCENT)

EDUCATION

ECPI University Networking & Security Management (A.A.S.) Newport News, VA September 2008 - May 2010